Arsenii Ashukha

Moscow & Amsterdam • ⋈ ars.ashuha@gmail.com • ars-ashuha.ru • github.com/ars-ashuha • 23 years old



Summary

I'm getting PhD at University of Amsterdam jointly with Yandex Research, focused on Bayesian Deep Learning by supervision of Dmitry Vetrov and Max Welling. Also, I teach several scientific seminars on Machine Learning and involved in research at HSE. My publications are available at Google Scholar.

Skills: Machine Learning, Deep Learning, Bayesian ML, Python, Linux, Fluent English

Education

2017 - 2021 Working on	PhD Candidate, Machine Learning, University of Amsterdam Bayesian Deep Learning by supervision of Dmitry Vetrov (Yandex) and Max Welling (UvA)	UNIVERSITY OF AMSTERDAM
2015 - 2017 Thesis	Master, Machine Learning, Moscow Institute of Physics and Technology, GPA: 4.8/5.0 Variational Dropout Sparsifies DNNs, Supervisor: Dmitry Vetrov (HSE), Alex Dral (MIPT)	NIPT -
2015 - 2016 Result	Irregular Student, Machine Learning, Yandex School of Data Analysis, GPA: 4.8/5.0 Six courses were passed and the favorites are Bayesian ML, Deep Learning, Machine Learning	SCHOOL OF DATA ANALYSIS
2011 - 2015	Bachelor, Computer Science, Bauman Moscow State Technical University, GPA: 3.7/5.0	

Building of Uncorrelated Kernels for Topic Models, Supervisor: N. Loukachevitch (MSU)

Publications

Thesis

- Kirill Neklyudov, Dmitry Molchanov, Arsenii Ashukha, Dmitry Vetrov Structured Bayesian Pruning via Log-Normal Multiplicative Noise, NIPS 2017, arxiv.org/abs/1705.07283
- Dmitry Molchanov*, Arsenii Ashukha*, Dmitry Vetrov Variational Dropout Sparsifies Deep Neural Networks, ICML 2017, arxiv.org/abs/1701.05369

Teaching

- Feb 2016 Feb 2017: Practical Lecturer of Machine Learning at MIPT (page)
- Feb 2017 Aug 2017: Lecturer of Deep Learning block in Machine Learning at MIPT (page)
- Oct 2016 Aug 2017: Lecturer of Deep Learning block in Data Mining in Action (page, video)
- Feb 2017 nowadays: Supervisor of Scientific seminar on Machine Learning at HSE (page) and YSDA (page)

Experience

Sep 2017 - nowadays	Yandex, Moscow — Researcher at Applied Research Team Chief: Dmitriy Vetrov (vetrovd@yandex.ru), Pavel Serdyukov (pavser@yandex.team.ru)	Y andex
Mar 2017 - nowadays	HSE, Moscow — Intern Researcher at Bayesian Deep Learning Lab Chief: Dmitriy Vetrov (vetrovd@yandex.ru)	HIGHER SCHOOL OF ECONOMICS
Jun 2016 - Aug 2016 3 months	Yandex, Moscow — Intern at Music Deep Learning Group - The quality of searching similar tracks and recommendation using DNN has been improved - Similar tracks system is working in production at music.yandex.ru Chief: Eugene Krofto (singleton@yandex-team.ru)	Y andex
Dec 2013 - Feb 2016 2 years part time	Rambler, Moscow — R&D Engineer at Machine Learning Group - The quality and the performance of user classification using url-history has been improved - Has been developed recommendations system for news posts on rambler.ru Chief: Pavel Klemenkov (pklemenkov@gmail.com), Anton Gorokhov (anton.gorokhov@gmail.com)	RAMBLER&Co
Jun 2013 - Aug 2013 3 months	Rambler, Moscow — Intern at Search Group - Has been developed query clf system to use widgets in a web search result adaptively Chief: Max Karpenko (v3dmax@gmail.com)	RAMBLER&Co